We're going to read verses 1-1 17.
Exodus the 20th chapter. We're going to
read verses 1 through 17.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> And God spake all these words.
>> Hold up one second. Make sure.
>> All right. We're going to take it from
the top again. Exodus 20, we're going to
read verses 1-1 17. And while we reading
the law, the kids are going to go to the
children's class. So, Exodus 20:es 1-1
17. When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> And God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord God, am
a jealous God, visiting the iniquity of
the fathers upon the children, unto the
third and fourth generation of them that
hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not give
take the name of the Lord thy God in
vain. For the Lord will not hold him
guiltless that taketh his name in vain.
Remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy. Sixth day shall thou labor and do
all thy work. But the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In it thou
shalt not do any work, thou nor thy son,
nor thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor
thy maidservant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hollowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land, which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
man's servant, nor his maid servant, nor
his ox, nor his ass, nor anything that
is thy neighbors.
>> Now, if you would please turn to
Ecclesiastes
the 12th chapter. Ecclesiastes 12, and
we're going to read verses 13 and verse
14.
Ecclesiastes the 12th chapter. We're
going to read verses 13
and we're going to read verses 14.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> Let us hear the conclusion of the whole
matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments. For this is the whole duty
of man. For God shall bring every work
into judgment with every secret thing,
whether it be good or whether it be
evil. Now, if you would
please turn to Revelation
22.
Revelation 22. Hold up one second.
Sorry about that. Got to make sure we
got this right. Praise the Lord.
Excuse me. Revelation 22
and we're going to read verses
and verse 15. Revelation the 22nd
chapter. We're going to read verses 14
and verse 15. When you get it, my
brother, please read.
>> Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they may have right to
the tree of life and may enter through
the gates into the city. For thou art
dogs, and sorcerers, and mongers,
and murderers, and idolattors, and so
whosoever loveth, and maketh a lie.
>> So that is the reading of the law.
So happy Sabbath, family.
>> I am brother Jeff, one of your teachers
here at the Birmingham Israel of God.
And reading for me is Brother Cameron.
It's his first time, so give him a big
applause.
>> You going have to read loud, brother.
>> That outdoor voice you got. I know you
got it.
>> So that everybody, not only the people
that's in here can hear you, but the
people that's on the internet as well.
>> And the title of today's lesson is this
light of mine, I'm going to let it
shine.
this light of mine, I'm going to let it
shine. Uh the light is your works. We
gonna see that in this lesson because
you letting that light, you letting your
work shine amongst men and women.
You showing your love of your God and
you showing your love of your neighbor.
So, this is a song that uh when when I
was little that we used to sing. My
grandmother had us singing this little
light of mine. I'm going to let it
shine. And you had to sing this at the
top of your lungs.
>> My grandmother played the accordion for
those that didn't know. Just a piano
that you do like this. And she played it
and we had to sing. You had tambourines
and some out baming on some drums and
everything else,
but we had to let our light shine. And
we also going to see that it's dealing
with the word as well. So you going to
have to put spread this word all over
the world as a light.
So the first place we're going to is is
Matthew the 5th chapter.
Matthew 5
and we're going to read verses 14 down
to verse 16.
Matthew the 5th chapter.
We're going to read verses 14
and verses 15.
So we going to take a look at some
things that this book going to tell us
who we are and what we supposed to do.
Matthew 5, give me verse 14, my brother,
when you get it.
>> Ye are the light of the world. A city
that is set on a hill cannot be hid.
>> That's right. So you are the light of
the world.
Say a city that is set on a hill cannot
be hid. So think about your highest hill
and you got a city sitting on that hill.
The light is going to shine. Everybody
can see that city sitting on that hill.
So that's the way you supposed to be in
this word. Read.
>> Neither do men light a candle and put it
under a bushel, but on a candlestick.
Yes. And it giveth light unto all that
are in the house.
>> So it giveth light to all that is in the
house. Give me verse 16.
>> Let your light so shine before men.
>> Yes.
>> That they may see your good works.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And glorify your father which is in
heaven.
>> Yes. So your light should shine
not only today
>> but your light should shine all the
other six days as well. Right?
>> So if you this is the day right here
that you come in and guess what you do?
You powering that light up.
>> So that light should be fully bright
>> tomorrow.
And definitely when you go back to that
work week, that light should be shining
bright
because this world makes that try to
make that light dim on you.
>> Cuz by the time Friday hit, that light
going in and out.
So that's why we had to come back on the
Sabbath day and charge that light up.
>> Let's go to our next place. Let's go to
John the 8th chapter.
John 8.
And I want y'all to hold y'all place in
the book of John cuz we're going to be
in and out of John.
John the 8th chapter. We're going to
read one verse.
Verse number 12.
John the 8th chapter. We're going to
read one verse. Verse number 12.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> Then spake Jesus again unto them,
saying, I am the light of the world.
>> So we see Jesus is the light of the
world.
Read.
>> He that followeth me shall not walk in
darkness.
>> Yes.
>> But shall have the light of life. but
shall have the light of life. So if you
following Christ, you have that light of
life. What light of life is that? Let's
go to go to John 6 and 63 and we going
to see what that light of life is.
John 6 and we're going to read one
verse, verse 63.
So you have to put this whole thing
together. So you have to go here a
little and there a little
>> to put this thing together
John 6. And we're going to read one
verse. Verse 63.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> It is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profiteth nothing.
>> Yes, sir.
>> The words that I speak unto you, they
are spirit and they are life. So those
words are spirit. Those words are life.
What words? The word of God.
>> It's spirit and it is life. This word
gives you life.
>> It gives you the main life is eternal
life. But it brings you out of a light a
life of darkness while you're on this
earth.
>> And it brings you into his light.
>> And that's the light that we want to be
in again, not only today.
But every day,
>> that's why you had to read this book
every day if you want that light to stay
bright. Cuz guess what? When Friday get
here, if you reading your book, that
light still going to be shining bright.
>> But if you ain't in that book, that
light going to be flickering and
blinking.
Just like y'all know how it is when
y'all done rolled that gas needle all
the way down to eat
>> and that light is is it's flickering and
all of a sudden it come on.
>> Let's go to Isaiah the eth chapter.
You about to run out.
But you know how we can make it.
Same way you don't take no chances with
that gas. You don't take no chance with
this word.
Isaiah the 8th chapter.
We're going to read verses 16 and 17.
Then we're going to skip down to verse
20. Scripts on the board. So, you can't
understand my mouth.
Isaiah 8
and we're going to read verses 16 and
17. Then we're going to skip down to
verse 20.
I'm going to let everybody get there.
When you get it, my brother, give me
Isaiah 8:16, please.
>> Bind up the testimony.
>> Yes. seal the law among my disciples.
>> And I will wait upon the Lord that
hideth his face from the house of Jacob.
>> Yes.
>> And I will look for him.
>> That's right. So he said, "Bind up the
testimony and seal the law amongst my
disciples." Disciples just simply a
follower of Christ.
>> That's what we supposed to be. Skip down
to verse 20 and read.
to the law and to the testimony.
>> So when it say to the law and to the
testimony, we talking about what man
called the Old Testament and the New
Testament.
>> Read.
>> If they speak not according to this
word, it is because there is no light in
them.
>> So you see that right there? If they
speak not according to this what? To
this word,
>> it's because there's no light in them.
So all them New Testament Christians
Sound like you ain't got no light in you
>> cuz it said to the law and to the
testimony.
>> Then all them old testament prophets if
YOU AIN'T GOT THAT testimony to
understand what the old is talking
about.
>> You'll like them too.
>> So you got to have them both.
>> Got to have them both.
>> Now let's go back to John. I hope you
got your marker there.
Let's go to John the 12th chapter. John
and we're going to read verses 35
to 37.
John the 12th chapter.
We're going to read verses
to 37.
I know y'all know like I know they'll
pass you out that little Bible
with just Matthew to Revelations and
then it may have Psalms and Proverbs in
it.
>> You got to have the whole book. You
can't have half of it.
John 12. Give me verse 35, my brother,
when you get.
>> Then Jesus said unto them, yet a little
while is the light with you.
>> Yes.
>> Walk while ye have the light, lest
darkness come upon you.
>> So you see what Jesus said? He letting
them know that I'm with you for a little
while. I am that light. Walk in me while
you can. Read. For he that walketh in
darkness knoweth not whether he goeth.
>> Yes.
>> While ye have light, believe in the
light, that ye may be the children of
light.
>> So that's what we come in here for. You
got to believe in this light so you can
be called what? The children of light.
And that's what we want to be the
children of light. Read
>> these things spake Jesus and departed
and did hide himself from them.
>> Yes.
>> But though he had done so many miracles
before them, yet they believed not on
him.
>> Do y'all see that right there? He did
all those miracles. If you read up into
this, it'll let you know they knew about
the Christ because they read the law and
they was living the testimony. So they
knew about Christ. But they they asked
the question, who is this son of man we
supposed to be lifting up?
>> If you would know who he was, you knew
he was the light. YOU WOULD ALREADY KNEW
who he was
>> and with the miracles and the things
that he done.
But man want to follow in his own ways
>> and do his own thing.
Let's go to Ephesians 5. Ephesians the
5th chapter.
And we're going to read verses one down
to verse eight.
And the sad part about it is
is he can come in the flesh right now.
>> People still won't be able to tell who
he is.
>> By the works that he do, you should be
able to tell who he was.
Ephesians 5, we're going to read verses
one down to verse 8.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> But ye therefore followers of God as
dear children, and walk in love as
Christ also hath loved us, and hath
given himself for us an offering, and a
sacrifice to God for a sweet smelling
savor.
>> Yes. But fornication and all
uncleanliness or covetedness, let it not
be once named among you, as becometh
saints.
>> Yes. So as becometh saints, you can't
have this name once among you. It say
once.
Read.
>> Neither filthiness nor foolish talking,
nor gesting, which are not convenient,
but rather giving of thanks.
>> Yes. For this ye know, that no
whoreonger, nor unclean person, nor
covetous man, who is in an idoltor, hath
any inheritance in the kingdom of Christ
and of God.
>> Yes.
>> Let no man deceiveth you with vain
words. For because of these things
cometh the wrath of God upon the
children of disobedience.
>> So we seen some children of light. Now
we see some children of disobedience.
You have to make a choice which one you
want to be.
>> Read.
>> Be not ye therefore partakers with them.
>> So it's you know how to separate
yourself. It tell you don't even partake
with them.
>> Read.
>> For ye were sometimes darkness. But now
are ye light in the Lord. Walk as
children of light.
>> So it's telling you to walk as that
child of the light.
>> Read. No. That's all I'm tell.
If you want to know how to walk, this is
telling you how to walk. If you don't
know,
>> if you got any questions on what you
supposed to do, we just read it. Put
this in your chest pocket.
>> Take it home and study it.
>> Let's go to First Thessalonians the 5th
chapter.
moving a little fast because we got a
lot of ground to cover. 1 Thessalonians
and we're going to read verses 1 down to
verse 10.
1 Thessalonians the 5th chapter. We're
going to read verses 1 down to verse 10.
Yeah. Here a few pages.
I want everybody to read this and see
this.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> But of the times and the seasons,
brethren, ye have no need that I write
unto you.
>> Yes.
>> For yourselves know perfectly that the
day of the Lord so cometh as a thief in
the night.
>> So you see what he said? He said, "But
of the times and the seasons, brethren,
ye have no need that I write unto you."
No need that I write unto you the time
of the season. Then what it say? For you
yourselves
know perfectly that the day of the Lord
so cometh as the thief in the night. We
ain't no need for us to talk about that
because he going to pop up when you
least expect it. But let's let the book
talk. Go ahead.
>> For when they shall say peace and
safety,
>> yes,
>> then sudden destruction cometh upon
them.
>> Uhhuh.
>> As travail upon a woman with child, and
they shall not escape.
>> Yes. But ye, brethren, are not in
darkness, that that that day should
overtake you as a thief.
>> Yes. So as long as you in that light,
that day ain't going to overtake you.
>> You prepared. You ready, you got oil in
your lamp.
>> Read.
>> Ye are all the children of light and the
children of the day. We are not of the
night nor of the darkness.
>> Yes. Come on. Therefore, let us not
sleep as do others, but let us watch and
be sober.
>> Yes, come on.
>> For they that sleep sleep in the night,
and they that be drunken are drunken in
the night.
>> Yes. Come on.
>> But let us who are of the day be sober,
putting on the breastplate of faith and
love, and for an inhelmet the hope of
salvation.
>> So this drunk is talking about, it ain't
talking about no wine.
>> It's talking about a spiritual
drunkenness. And the darkness is talking
about a spiritual darkness. Darkness
where? IN THE MIND. YOU DRUNK IN THE
MIND.
>> Go ahead.
>> For God hath not appointed us to wrath.
>> Yes.
>> But to obtain salvation by our Lord
Jesus Christ.
>> Come on.
>> Who died for us that whether we wake or
sleep, we should live together with him.
>> Yes, sir. that whether we in the grave
or we alive that what we going to be
with him.
>> So that's the whole thing about it is is
that if you walking in this word and you
walking in that light, God forbid you
get taken away and put to sleep in the
ground, guess what? He's still going to
call you out of that ground
>> in that first resurrection. That's what
you want. Yes,
>> that's your whole plan of being here.
>> If you're playing anything else, you
need to re you need to come up with
another game plan. Get you a new coach.
Obviously, you got the wrong coach
coaching your team.
>> Let's go to Leviticus the 11th chapter.
Jesus is the head coach, the CEO, the
general, whatever you want to call it.
>> So, obviously, you got a different
coach.
Leviticus 11th chapter, we're going to
read verses 34 down to 36. I mean Luke,
>> Luke the 11th chapter. I was trying to
get y'all some dietary law.
Somebody must need it in the house.
>> Luke the 11th chapter. We're going to
read verses 34 to 36.
Luke 11,
we're going to read verses 34
to 36.
When you get it, my brother,
please read
>> the light of the body is the eye.
>> So look at that. The light of the body
is the eye. We ain't talking about
these.
This your eye. This what guides you
right here. This what sees for you.
>> Go ahead. Therefore, when thine eye is
single, thy whole body is full of light.
>> But when thine eye is evil, thy body
also is full of darkness.
>> Yes.
>> Take heed, therefore, that the light
which is in thee be not darkness.
>> Yes.
>> If thy whole body therefore be full of
light, having no part dark, the whole
shall be full of light. As when the
bright shining of a candle doth give
thee light.
>> So think about this.
When Moses went up and was with the
Lord, what happened to Moses' face?
>> Start to shine. He around that word.
>> So that's what the word does. The word
changes you.
>> You start to shine.
>> People notice the difference in you.
>> YOU DON'T HAVE TO SAY A WORD. YOU AIN'T
GOT TO TELL THEM, I GO TO Israel of God
Bible stud. We keep the Sabbath day. You
ain't got TO SAY NOTHING. THEY GOING TO
ASK YOU.
THEY GOING to ask you.
So your life got to your whole body got
to be that light. Think about Enoch. IT
SAID ENOCH WALKED with God and then he
was not because God took him. WHY? THAT
LIGHT OVERTTO HIM.
>> Let's go to first Peter the 2 chapter.
1 Peter 2,
we're going to read verse five. Then
we're going to skip down to verses 9 to
12.
First Peter
the 2 chapter.
We're going to read verse 5.
Then we're going to skip down to verses
nine. We're going to read nine all the
way down to verse 12.
Somebody got a phone on. Mute your
phone. We going to start over. Y'all
going to be here till the sun go down.
Got a long lesson.
First Peter 2.
Give me verse five, my brother, when you
get it.
>> Ye also, as lively stones are built up a
spiritual house and holy priesthood to
offer up spiritual sacrifices acceptable
to God by Jesus Christ. Yeah. So in this
chapter right here when we read, we got
Peter talking to Israel, letting Israel
know that they are a holy priesthood.
>> Skip down to verse nine and read.
>> But ye are a chosen generation.
>> Yes.
>> A royal priesthood.
>> Uhhuh. and holy nation, a peculiar
people, that ye should show forth the
praises of him who hath called you out
of darkness into his marvelous light.
>> Yes. So, we are peculiar people. People
wondering why you all dressed up and you
got your head covered.
>> Where you going today?
>> Like the lesson says something about
that woman.
>> Where she going?
Three,
>> which in time past were not a people.
>> Yes.
>> But are now the people of God,
>> which had not obtained mercy, but now
have obtained mercy.
>> Yes.
>> Dearly beloved, I beseech you as
strangers and pilgrims, abstain from
fleshly lusts, which war against the
soul.
>> Yeah. It wars against the body. Read.
having your conversation honest among
the Gentiles,
>> that whereas they speak against you as
evildoers, they may by your good works,
which they shall behold, glorify God in
the day of visitation." So look what it
said. Having your conversation honest
amongst the Gentiles,
that whereas they speak against you as
evil doers,
they may be your good works. So think
about it.
If you on the job or wherever it is you
at and people talking evil and talking
bad about you, but you know that ain't
true, you ain't got to open your mouth
and say a word. Let your word speak for
you that that gentile person can come or
whoever it may be come and say, "Oh, no,
that ain't brother Jeff."
>> Oh no, that ain't brother Alex.
>> He don't operate like that.
>> You don't have to say a word. Let your
work stand for you.
>> Where we at?
>> That was it.
>> That was all 11. Yep.
>> 12.
>> Okay. So, let's go to Acts the 13th
chapter.
Acts 13.
Well, a lot of times we open our mouth
up when it ain't time to speak.
The Lord tell you is a time and a place
for everything.
>> So if you laid those good works out, you
ain't got to say a word.
That man will stand up and fight for
you.
I'm starting to notice that on the job
because I didn't change how I was.
People
start to say, "Well, no, Jeff ain't
going to do that. He going to be here.
He going to be on the job. He going to
do this and that." So on and so forth.
>> Acts 13,
we're going to read verses 46 to 49.
Acts the 13th chapter, we're going to
read verses 46
to 49.
Get it, my brother. Please read.
>> Then Paul and Barnabas waxed bold and
said, "It was necessary that the word of
God should first have been spoken to
you."
>> Yes. Talking to Israel. Come on.
>> But seeing ye put it from you and judge
yourselves unworthy of everlasting life.
Lo, we turn to the Gentiles.
>> Wow. That's power. Some powerful words
to say to a man. You what? You did your
own self. You judge the word unworthy
unto your own self unto everlasting
life. So what? It turned to the
Gentiles. Read.
>> For so hath the Lord commanded us,
saying, I have set thee to be a light of
the Gentiles.
>> Uhhuh.
>> That thou shouldest be for salvation
unto the ends of the earth.
>> Yes.
>> And when the Gentiles heard this, they
were glad and glorified the word of the
Lord. And as many as were ordained to
eternal life believed.
>> Yes. Come on.
>> And the word of the Lord was published
throughout all the region.
>> Yes. So when them Gentiles heard that
word and they heard that they was
accepted because Israel was saying the
word was for them only and we got some
Hebrew brothers that's still saying the
same thing. Well obviously they stuck in
the law. Right. Right.
>> But then they try to come to the
testimony a little bit and then they'll
tell you that what Jesus said go on to
the what the lost sheep of the house of
Israel. But then you got to remember
that what Paul and Peter Peter was first
sent to who? Cornelius.
>> Who was Cornelius? Cornelius was a
gentile. Then we seen Paul. What? Let me
hush about Paul because he in his
lesson. So we going to let the lesson
tell you about Paul.
Let's go to Isaiah
the 48th chapter.
>> My eyes bad. Isaiah, is it 49 or 48? I
can't see.
>> 49.
>> Isaiah 49. I'm sorry. I got to make
these letters bigger.
Isaiah 49.
and we're going to read verses 1 down to
7.
Isaiah the 49th chapter
and we're going to read verses 1 down to
verse 7.
But we going to see what we just read.
Say along to the testimony then it
>> 49. Give me verse one, my brother.
Listen, O isles unto me, and hearken ye
people from afar.
>> Yes,
>> the Lord hath called me from the womb,
from the bowels of my mother hath he
made mention of my name. And he hath
made my mouth like a sharp sword, and
the shadow of his hand hath he hid me.
And made me a polished shaft, and his
quiver hath he hid me. and said unto me,
"Thou art my servant, O Israel, in whom
I will be glorified."
>> Yes.
>> Then I said, I have labored in vain. I
have spent my strength for not, and in
vain, yet surely my judgment is with the
Lord, and my work with my God.
>> Uh-huh. And now saith the Lord that
formed me from the womb to be his
servant to bring Jacob again to him
through Israel be not gathered yet shall
I be glorious in the eyes of the Lord
and my God shall be my strength.
>> Come on.
>> And he said it is a light thing that
thou shouldest be my servant to raise up
the tribes of Jacob.
>> to raise up the tribes of Jacob or in
other words to raise up Israel.
Come on. So he's separating who he
talking about.
>> But again, let me let the book talk. Go
ahead.
>> And to restore the preserved of Israel.
>> Yes.
>> I will also give thee for a light to the
Gentiles.
>> So did he not say also?
>> Give thee for a light unto the Gentiles
that what?
>> Give me a second.
>> Finish that up. Matter of fact, take six
from the top then. Come on. And he said,
"It is a light thing that thou shouldest
be my servant to raise up the tribes of
Jacob, and to restore the preserved of
Israel.
>> Yes,
>> I will also give thee for a light to the
Gentiles."
>> That what?
>> Go ahead.
>> That thou mayest be my salvation unto
the end of the earth.
>> That you may be my salvation unto the
end of the earth. And what else?
>> And verse seven.
>> Yep. Thou saith the Lord the redeemer of
Israel and his holy one. To him whom men
despiseth to him whom the nation
abhoreth to a servant of rulers, kings
shall see and arise. Princes also shall
worship because of the Lord that is
faithful and the holy one of Israel and
he shall choose thee.
>> So we see both the father and the son
and right here and we in the book of
Isaiah.
better read your Bible.
Let's go to 1 Timothy the 6th chapter.
1 Timothy 6.
So it would prophesied that that light
had to go to the Gentiles that we had to
be a light unto the Gentiles.
But we are light to everybody cuz we a
royal priesthood.
We holy in the eyes of God where we
supposed to be holy.
1 Timothy the 6th chapter
and we're going to read verses 17
to verse 20.
1 Timothy the 6th chapter. We going to
read verses 17
to 20.
Get it, my brother.
Please read.
>> Charge them that are rich in this world,
that they be not high- minded, nor trust
in uncertain riches, but in the living
God, who giveth us richly all things to
enjoy.
>> Yes, he does. Come on.
>> That they do good. that they be rich in
good works, ready to distribute, willing
to communicate.
>> Yeah. So that's the riches that you want
to have.
>> Rich and good works.
>> Taking his word out. Read
>> laying up in store for themselves a good
foundation against the time to come.
>> Yes. Cuz it's a time to come, man. That
hey, we ain't never seen before. No man
has seen. And what else?
>> That they may lay hold on eternal life.
That's the whole game plan is to lay
hold on to eternal life.
>> Finish that up.
>> Oh, Timothy, keep that which is
committed to thy trust, avoiding profane
and vain babblings and oppositions of
science falsely so-called.
>> Yeah. So, that's goes for us as well. We
got to avoid them things as well cuz
it's out here, family. And if you on
that book and social media, you'll see
it all day long.
Israel is overrighteous.
John the third chapter should have John
held.
John 3 and we're going to read verses 16
to 21.
John the 3 chapter.
We're going to read verses 16 to 21. I
know everybody in here familiar with
John 3:16
cuz back in the uh 80s
every sporting event you went to
somebody were holding up a sign John
3:16.
John 3:16.
So if you wondering what it was
hopefully you picked up your Bible and
even looked but hopefully you read
beyond 16 because it gonna give you a
little more.
John 3, give me verse 16, my brother,
when you get it.
>> For God so loved the world that he gave
his only begotten son that whosoever
believeth in him should not perish but
have everlasting life.
>> Yes, sir. Come on.
>> For God sent not his son into the world
to condemn the world.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But that the world through him might be
saved.
>> Oh, so might be saved.
>> He didn't say that he was going to save
the world. It said might be saved.
That's right.
>> Read.
>> He that believeth on him is not
condemned.
>> Uhhuh. So that one qualification right
there. You got to believe on him.
>> See, you're not condemned. What?
>> The Sorry. But he that believeth not is
condemned already.
>> Yes.
>> But he hath not believed in the name of
the only begotten son of God.
>> Yes. Because he hath not believed in the
name of the only begotten son of God.
Come on.
And this is the condemnation that light
is come into the world and men love the
darkness rather than the light.
>> So look at this right here. Men love the
darkness instead of the light. And it's
going to tell you why.
>> Read.
>> Because their deeds were evil.
>> Because their deeds were evil. And what?
>> For everyone that doeth evil hateth the
light.
>> Yes. Neither cometh to the light, lest
his deeds should be reproved.
>> So look at that. You going to vote? No,
man. Y'all go ahead, bro. I'll catch you
next Saturday.
>> No, man. Uh, right now I'm in a hurry,
right? I ain't got time to take your fly
out here, man. I I catch up with y'all
later. Where you say your church at?
Well, they take information. Okay then,
man. Y'all going to come check y'all
out.
>> But then you realize that word going to
do what? It's going to reprove you. It's
going to put that light on what you
doing evil.
>> Then now guess what you got to do? YOU
GOT TO MAKE A DECISION. Am I going to
stop and turn to the Lord or I'm going
to continue in the way that I'm walking?
>> You got to make a decision. And some
people ain't ready to make that decision
right now.
>> Cuz they don't feel the time is at hand.
>> Keep going.
But he that doeth truth cometh to the
light, that his deeds may be made
manifest, that they are wrought in God.
>> So we run into that light.
>> We want to let it be known, Lord, I'm
doing everything I can to push forward
with your kingdom.
>> We going to stand in that light. We
ain't trying to hide.
Proverbs 4.
Proverbs the 4th chapter.
And we're going to look at verses 14
down to 22, Proverbs, the 4th chapter.
And we're going to read verses 14 down
to verse 22.
We got to let that light shine, family.
We got to shine. If we in here
>> and all those other truth keepers, if
you really in this, you got to let that
light shine.
>> Proverbs 4, give me verse 14, my
brother.
>> Enter not into the path of the wicked,
and go not in the way of evil men.
>> Yes.
>> Avoid it. pass not by it, turn from it,
and pass away.
>> So look what it's saying. It's telling
you not to enter into that path. It's
telling you to do what? Avoid it.
>> You know what they doing over there
>> cuz you KNOW THE ONES THAT'S DOING IT.
>> They said avoid it. Pass not by. If I
got to go all the way over here, I need
to go right over there and get my bag.
But I know what's right over there. I'm
going out that door and I'm going all
the way around because I know if I go
over here and I got to deal with them,
then what? I may not be strong enough to
handle it.
>> I may fall into what they doing.
>> We got to remember everybody ain't as
strong as we are. Everybody vices and
temptations is different.
>> Mine is different from yours. Yours is
different from mine. You might be able
to walk over there through there and
speak. Hey, how y'all doing? Whatever.
Uh, I'mma holl at y'all later. Go get
your stuff and go on. But I might, man.
Yeah. What's going on? And next thing
you know, I sat down,
brother.
>> Some people just ain't strong enough to
turn away.
>> So, DON'T GO. THAT'S WHY IT'S TELLING
YOU TO AVOID IT. DON'T GO OVER THERE.
>> Don't go.
read.
>> For they sleep not except they have done
mischief and their sleep is taken away
unless they cause some to fall.
>> Yes.
>> For they eat the bread of wickedness and
drink the wine of violence.
>> So look what they doing. Go ahead.
>> But the path of the just is as the
shining light
>> that shineth more and more onto the
perfect day.
>> Yes, it does. Come on.
>> The way of the wicked is as darkness.
They know not what they stumble.
My son, attend to my words. Incline
thine ear unto my sayings.
>> Let them not depart from thine eyes.
>> Yes.
>> Keep them in the midst of thine heart.
>> Uh-huh.
>> For they are life unto those that find
them and health to all their flesh.
>> So look what it say. He says, "Words is
life
>> unto those that find them."
>> So once you find them, hold on to them.
And don't take it for granted
>> and thank you strong
>> and you can do this and you can do that
and you find yourself right back out
there again.
>> Telling you they don't even call me no
more.
Thank you, Lord.
>> I used to get that phone call and get
talked about all the time.
>> They don't even call no more. I I ain't
Listen, this word right here tell you
what it does. It sanctifies you.
>> It separates you. It sets you apart.
>> So, when you don't see something in
common, what you do?
And then you realize you saying to
yourself, man, it ain't nothing I did.
>> The word did it.
>> ALL YOU GOT TO DO IS JUST let the Lord
work. A lot of time we try to what what
I need to call and tell them the reason
why I YOU AIN'T GOT TO TELL THEM
NOTHING.
>> THE WORD GOING TO DO IT.
>> You ain't got to say nothing to them.
>> Let's go to Acts nine.
We going to read verses one
>> down to verse 17.
>> Acts 9,
we going to read verses one
down to verse 17.
>> So now what we talked about earlier
about Saul, I mean about Saul becoming
Paul, we going to see it in the book.
That's why I said let me hush my mouth
and let this book talk cuz it's talking
today.
Acts 9, give me verse one.
>> And Saul yet breathing out threatenings
and slaughter against the disciples of
the Lord, went onto the high priest.
>> Yes.
>> And desired of him letters to Damascus
to the synagogues, that if he found any
of this way, whether they were men or
women, he might bring them bound onto
Jerusalem.
>> That what Paul did. Paul was what? He
persecuted the church.
>> He was there when Stephan got stoned.
Read.
>> And as he journeyed, he came near
Damascus, and he suddenly there shined
round about him a light from heaven.
>> Yes. Come on.
>> And he fell to the earth, and heard a
voice saying unto him, "Saul, Saul, why
persecutest me thou me?"
>> Yes. So that's the thing about it is
they ain't hurting. You ain't hurting
that individual.
>> You hurting God. Because what it said
you are, you said you are a child, a
children of the light.
>> So when they persecute you, if you
walking in this word, they ain't hurting
you.
>> Come on, read.
>> And he said, Who art thou, Lord?
>> Yes.
>> And the Lord said, I am Jesus, whom thou
persecutest?
>> Look at that.
>> It is hard for thee to kick against the
pricks.
>> Uhhuh. And he and he trembling and
astonished said, Lord, what wil thou
have me do? And the Lord said unto him,
Arise, and go into the city, and it
shall be told thee what thou must do.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And the men which journeyed with him
stood speechless, hearing a voice, but
seeing no man.
>> And Saul arose from the earth, and when
his eyes were opened, he saw no man. But
they led him by the hand and brought him
into Damascus. And he was three days
without sight. And neither did he eat
nor drink.
>> Yeah. So his sight was taken. So he
didn't eat or drink. He fasting. He
trying to figure out what's going on.
>> Read.
>> And there was a certain disciple at
Damascus named Ananas. And to him said
the Lord in a vision, Ananas. And he
said, "Behold, I am here." And the Lord
said unto him, "Arise, and go into the
street which is called straight, and
inquire in the house of Judas, for one
called Saul of Tarsus, for behold, he
prayth."
>> Look at that. So what Saul doing when
all that hit him? Hey, he fell down on
his knee. He still to forget how to
pray.
>> He trying to find out what's going on.
>> I DONE LOST MY SIGHT.
>> So he fast. SO WHEN SOMETHING COME OVER
YOU SOMETIME YOU HAD TO put some things
down around you. You had to go into
silence. Had to like it said go in your
prayer closet and find out what's going
on.
>> Come on.
>> And hath seen in a vision a man named
Ananas coming in and putting his hand on
him.
>> Yes.
>> That he might receive his sight.
>> Uhhuh. Then Ananas answered, "Lord, I
have heard by many of this man how much
evil he hath done to thy saints at
Jerusalem."
>> So look at that. Everybody scared of
Paul was which was Saul at this time.
They heard about what he did. The church
heard and when they see it was just like
what they said Debo.
They running.
>> It was no took YOUR CHAIN. JUST GET OUT
OF THE WAY.
READ.
>> And here he hath authority from the
chief priest to bind all that call on
thy name. But
>> so look at that. He even had authority
from the chief priest to do what he was
doing.
>> Read.
>> But the Lord said unto him, "Go thy way,
for he is a chosen vessel unto me to
bear my name before the Gentiles."
>> Yes, sir.
>> And kings and the children of Israel.
So, do we notice that we see Gentiles?
>> That's right.
>> And the children of Israel.
>> So, it look like to me you can't call
that Gentile Israelite
>> cuz he going to bear witness to give
that word to everybody.
>> He going to give it to everybody.
>> And look, these are words coming from
the high priest.
>> So, we don't care nothing about what the
chief priest said. I said, "Do this."
>> Read,
>> "For I will show him how great things he
must suffer for my name's sake."
>> Yes. And Ananas went his way and entered
into the house, and putting his hands on
him, said, "Brother Saul, the Lord, even
Jesus, that appeared unto thee in the
way as thou camest, hath sent me, that
thou mightest receive thy sight, and be
filled with the Holy Ghost."
>> Yes, sir. Being filled with the Holy
Ghost, filled with the word. Yes.
>> So now we going to read the rest of that
on your own, but we going to go to Acts
26.
We sticking with the story, but we
advancing on.
Acts the 26th chapter.
We're going to read verses 12
down to verse 29.
Acts 26.
We going to read verses 12
down to verse 29.
A few pages. We're going to continue
this. When you get it, my brother,
please read. Whereupon as I went to
Damascus with authority and commission
from the chief priests
>> at midday, O king, I saw in the way a
light from heaven above the brightness
of the sun shining round about me and
them which journeyied with me.
>> So this power running down, what
happened to me? Go ahead.
And when we were all fallen to the
earth, I heard a voice speaking unto me
and saying in the Hebrew tongue, Saul,
Saul, why persist thou me? It is hard
for thee to kick against the pricks.
>> Yes, come on.
>> And I said, Who art thou, Lord? And he
said, I am Jesus, whom thou persecutest.
>> Come on. But rise and stand upon thy
feet. For I have appeared unto thee for
this purpose, to make thee a minister
and a witness, both of these things
which thou hast seen, and of those
things in which I will appear unto thee.
>> Delivering thee from the people, and
from the Gentiles, unto whom now I send
thee.
>> Yes.
>> To open their eyes, and to turn them
from darkness to light.
>> Yeah. So we see the Gentiles were in
darkness. But this is what Israel
supposed to do. We supposed to turn them
from darkness to light. Not only our
people, but all people.
>> Read.
>> To open their eyes and to turn from the
darkness to light and from the power of
Satan onto God.
>> Yes. Because you know the book said
Gentiles, they do what? They sacrifice
unto devils.
>> Go ahead. that they may receive
forgiveness of sins and inheritance
among them which are sanctified by faith
that is in me.
>> Yes, it is. Come on.
>> Whereupon, O king Agrippa, I was not
disobedient unto the heavenly vision.
>> Yes. but shued first onto them of
Damascus and at Jerusalem and throughout
all the coast of Judea and then to the
Gentiles that they should repent and
turn to God
>> and do works meet for repentance.
>> Yes, sir. Got to put in them works, man.
For repentance. Come on.
>> For these causes the Jews caught me in
the temple and went about to kill me.
>> So now he running down all what happened
to him in between from what we just
read. So Israel ready to kill him
because just like some of them thinking
now they thought then that hey what are
you taking this word to the Gentiles
for? It's Israel only. Go ahead.
>> Having therefore obtained
Having therefore obtained help of God, I
continue on this day witnessing both to
small and great, saying none other
things than those which the prophets and
Moses did say should come.
>> Wait a minute. Oh, is this brother Paul
talking?
>> Did brother Paul say what? Saying none
other things than those which the
prophets and Moses did say should come.
>> So it sound like SOME PEOPLE BE LYING ON
BROTHER PAUL.
>> Paul brought a new way,
>> new dispensation. No, Paul just told you
what he brought.
>> Read. that Christ should suffer and that
he should be the first that should arise
for the dead and should light unto the
people and to the Gentiles.
>> Yes, sir. Come on.
>> And as he thus spake for himself, Fesus
said with a loud voice, Paul, thou art
beside thyself.
>> Come on.
>> Much learning doth make thee mad.
>> Yes. So he's saying, well, man, you've
been with read too many books, too much
learning, and turn you mad.
read.
>> But he said, "I am not mad, most noble
Fesus, but speak forth the words of
truth and soberness."
>> Yes, sir. Soberness of mine. Come on.
>> For the king knoweth of these things,
before whom also I speak freely, for I
am persuaded that none of these things
are hidden from him. For this thing was
not done in a corner.
>> All right, let's see what a grippa gonna
say. Come on. King of Grippa, believest
thou the prophets?
>> So he asked him a question. Queen King
of Griffle, believeth now the prophets.
So do you BELIEVE WHAT THE PROPHETS SAY?
And what else?
>> I know that thou believest.
>> I know you believe. Go ahead.
>> Then a gripper said unto Paul, almost
thou persuadest me to be a Christian.
>> Look at that. Gripper saying, whoa, you
almost persuaded me to be a father of
this Christ that y'all talking about cuz
he see the truth in it. But let's see
what Paul said.
>> And Paul said, I would I would to God
that not only thou, but also all that
hear me this day
>> were both almost and alltogether such as
I am accept THESE BONDS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT. SO I WISH THAT ALL WAS
EXACTLY LIKE ME, A follower of Christ
except having these bonds on being in
bondage for serving Christ.
>> So yeah, gripper be LIKE ME.
SO THAT'S WHAT WE SUPPOSED TO SAY. AIN'T
NO BE LIKE MIKE.
>> Be like me as I be like Christ.
>> Let's go to Philippians the 2 chapter.
>> Philippians 2
and we're going to read verses 14
to 16.
Philippians
the second chapter
>> and we're going to read verses 14
down to verse 16.
So we going to see like Paul was trying
to tell him, "Hey man, you got to set
yourself apart.
>> You going to be a follower of Christ.
That's what you doing. You setting
yourself apart from the world because we
know who the god of this world is. Satan
the devil.
>> Philippians 2. Give me verse 14, my
brother, when you get it.
>> And many of the brethren of the Lord
waxing confident by my bonds.
>> You in Philippians 2.
>> Yes. Wait. Philippians 2:14.
>> Yeah. Verse 14.
>> I'm sorry.
>> Yeah. Hey, no problem. You had me double
checking, too.
Praise the Lord, brother. We good.
>> All right, one time.
>> All right, go ahead.
>> Do all things without murmurings and
disputings,
>> that ye may be blameless and harmless,
the sons of God, without rebuke, in the
midst of a crooked and perverse nation.
>> Yes.
>> Among whom ye shine as lights in the
world.
>> So that's what you got to do amongst
this crooked and perverse generation.
You got to let your light shine, but you
got to do it without. Cuz trust me, when
they come to you, like I said, on the
job, I use the job as an example all the
time and they think they got you, when
they come to you asking you doing some,
unless they asking you to do something
crazy that'll get you hurt, they think
sometime they ask you to do stuff, they
watching you and see how you going to
respond cuz they definitely watch me cuz
I used to respond crazy. So they
definitely watching me. So now I can
say, "Okay, I got you."
That's how I was able to turn one of the
managers in my favor
>> because he came to me and asked me to do
something. Then he came back to me and
asked me to do it again. I said, "I got
you." I went and got him and got him all
the information he wanted and brought it
back to him. He said, "Man, I appreciate
that, man. What they say about you ain't
true."
>> I ain't even ask him what it was
>> cuz they might be listening.
I pray they are.
>> Where we at, brother?
>> 16.
>> Go ahead.
>> Holding forth the word of life that I
may rejoice in the day of Christ that I
have not run in vain.
>> Yes.
>> Neither labored in vain.
>> Yes. And we Hey, you have to know for
sure. That's where your faith come in
at. That you ain't doing this in vain.
>> Read that was That was it.
>> That was it. That was it.
>> I was looking at something else. Maybe I
shouldn't have put it in the list.
>> I'm sneak it in if you want.
>> No, we good cuz we got a we got a few
more we got to do. Let's go to second
Peter the first chapter.
Second Peter 1
and we're going to read verses 16 to 21.
Second Peter
the first chapter.
and we going to read verses
to 21.
So we ain't running it. We ain't just
out here doing this for nothing.
>> I'm telling you sometimes though, that's
why I said you have to sometimes you
just that social media stuff, man. And I
know we got brothers and sisters on
Facebook and all these other outlets and
we be want to say something to our
brothers and sisters on there when they
post something. You know, we want to
like they post. But guess what? The
enemy post always pop up too. And
normally his post be the first one that
pop up. His or her post be the first
ones that pop up on your page. And now
it didn't turn that spirit of the mind
bad on you. Here they go talking about
this and here they go talking about
that. Then you scroll past it and boom,
there go another one that popped up.
But you can't let that shake you. You
can't let it shake you.
>> Second Peter 1, give me verse 16, my
brother.
>> For we have not followed cunningly
devised fables.
>> Yes.
>> When we made known unto you the power
and coming of our Lord Jesus Christ, but
were witnesses of his majesty.
>> Uhhuh. For he received from God the
Father honor and glory. When there came
such a voice to him from the excellent
glory, this is my beloved son in whom I
am well pleased.
>> Yes.
>> And this voice which came from heaven,
we heard when we were with him in the
holy mount.
>> Uhhuh.
>> We have also more sure word of prophecy.
>> So look at that. He telling you we have
a more sure word of prophecy. What?
where unto ye do well that ye take heed
as unto a light that shineth in a dark
place until the day dawn and the day
star arises in your hearts.
>> Yes. So that more word of prophecy is
what they call the old testament that
law
>> read
>> knowing this first that no prophecy of
the scripture is of any private
interpretation.
>> Yes sir. For the for the prophecy came
not in old time by the will of man, but
holy men of God spake as they were moved
by the Holy Ghost.
>> Put this in your chest pocket
>> cuz somebody going to come and tell you
that man wrote the Bible.
>> Read that 21 again.
>> For the prophecy came not in old time by
the will of man.
>> IT DIDN'T COME BY NO WILL OF MAN, BUT
WHAT? But holy men of God spake as they
were moved by the Holy Ghost.
>> spake as they were moved by the Holy
Ghost.
>> And you can go to Revelation 1 and one
and it'll show you how the protocol
operates.
>> The father gave it to the son, the son
gave it to the gave it to the angel and
the angel gave it to the man. That's
that Holy Ghost. But what did the angel
give man? The word that came from the
father.
It don't change.
Let's go to John the first chapter. John
1 and we going to read verses 1 to 12.
We going to kind of look at that even in
this John one.
When I tell you y'all hear me say it all
the time, shut up, Jeff, and let the
book talk cuz it going to come out.
John the first chapter. We're going to
read verses one down to verse 12.
>> So, we're now
>> chapter two.
>> Oh, I skipped something.
>> I'm sorry. First John the 2 chapter. I'm
sorry. Y'all forgive me. First John the
2 chapter. I I found my highlighter
through the wrong thing.
>> First John 2. Appreciate it. That's why
you got this reader right here next to
you. You keep me in line. You get too
happy of him.
Settle down.
First John 2, we're going to read verses
1 to 11.
First John the 2 chapter, we're going to
read verses 1 to 11.
1 John 2
and we're going to read verses 1 down to
verse 11.
When you get it, my brother, please
read.
>> My little children, these things write I
unto you,
>> that ye sin not. And if any man sin, we
have an advocate with the father, Jesus
Christ the righteous. And he is the
propitiation for our sins, and not for
ours only, but also for the sins of the
whole world.
>> Yes. And hereby we do know that we know
him if we keep his commandments.
>> Yes sir. So when you read that John 3:16
for God so loved the world that he gave
his only begotten son and you come right
here and you tie it in because it said
the same thing that he is a perpetuation
for our sins and not ours only but also
for the sins of the whole world. But the
only way you going to know him and he
know you if you doing what?
>> Keeping his commandments. Read. He that
saith, I know him, and keepeth not his
commandments, is a liar, and the truth
is not in him.
>> That what the book say, read.
>> But whosoever keepeth his word, in him
verily is the love of God perfected.
Hereby know we that we are in him.
>> Yes, sir. Come on.
>> He that saith, he abideth in him ought
himself also so to talk.
>> So to walk. So to walk,
he that saith he abideth in him ought
himself also so to walk even as he
walked.
>> Yeah. So you want to know how to do? If
you say he abide in you, you going to
walk the same way he walked when he was
in the flesh.
>> Read.
>> Brethren, I write no new commandment
onto you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> But an old commandment which ye had from
the beginning. The old commandment is
the word which ye have heard from the
beginning.
>> Yes. Again, a new commandment I write
unto you.
>> Which thing is true in him and in you,
because the darkness is passed, and the
true light now shineth.
>> Yes. The true light now shineth.
Exactly. Come on.
>> He that saith he is in the light and
hateth his brother is in darkness even
until now.
>> Yes.
>> He that loveth his brother abideth in
the light, and there is none occasion of
stumbling in him.
>> Uh-huh. But he that hateth his brother
is in darkness,
>> and walketh in darkness, and knoweth not
whether he goeth, because that darkness
hath blinded his eyes.
>> Yes, sir.
>> So hopefully we ain't got no hate for
our brothers and our sisters in this
room
>> and outside of this room.
>> Can't have it.
>> You can't say you a follower of Christ
and you got that hatred in your heart.
Ain't nobody telling you to go out here
and and make a fool of yourself and
somebody that did something to you in
hers and you keep on running up behind
them.
>> Got to be wise.
>> But I tell you, be as wise as serpents,
but what
>> is as a dove?
>> I understand that you going to bite me.
So guess what I'm going to do? Hey, how
you doing? Happy Sabbath. That's the
only time I see you or if I see you
anywhere else. Hey, how you doing? You
doing all right? Okay, that's good. And
keep it moving.
>> But guess what? If they in darkness and
that light all all of a sudden shine on
them, y'all might become the two best
buds there is.
>> You never know. Let God work.
>> Now, let's go to John the first chapter.
Can I go there now, my brother?
>> Oh, for sure.
>> Okay.
John the 1 chapter
and we're going to read verses 1 down to
verse 12.
John the first chapter. We're going to
read verse one down to verse 12.
So we going to look at Jesus and we also
going to deal with John the Baptist as
well. John 1, give me verse one, my
brother.
>> In the beginning was the word. Yes.
>> And the word was with God and the word
was God.
>> That's right. So in the beginning we got
the word
and the word was with God and the word
was God. They tried to tell you. We know
this word is Jesus. So you got a lot of
them try to tell you that Jesus was God.
But what the book say?
>> Book tell you that he was. So you can't
go by what a man tell you. Man will
deceive you.
>> Give me verse two.
>> The same was in the beginning with God.
Mhm. Mhm.
>> All things were made by him.
>> Yes.
>> And without him was not anything made
that was made.
>> Yes.
>> In him was life and the life was the
light of men.
>> So look at that. In him was life and the
life was the light of men. Men shine.
>> Read.
>> And the light shineth in darkness and
the darkness comprehended it not.
>> Yes. There was a man sent from God whose
name was John. The same came for a
witness to bear witness of the light
that all men through him might believe.
>> Yes,
>> he was not that light but was sent to
bear witness of that light
>> cuz they thought John was him at one
time.
>> Read.
>> That was the true light which lightth
every man that cometh into the world.
Yes,
>> he was in the world, and the world was
made by him, and the world knew him not.
>> Yes,
>> he came unto his own, and his own
received him not. But as many as
received him, to them gave he power to
become the sons of God, even to them
that believe on his name.
>> Yes, sir. Cuz it's power in that name.
So, like we say all the time, take your
kick ball shoes off cuz we got them ones
that want to kick against the name of
Jesus.
>> You're going to break your toe.
>> Like I told you, they stumbled on that
what the stone that the builders
disallowed.
>> And that stone end up becoming what? The
head of the corner.
>> So, they were kicking on him at that
time. They still kicking on him to this
day. What they call modern day
Pharisees.
Let's go to Luke the first chapter.
Let's continue with what we was talking
about this uh Jesus and John.
Luke 1, we're going to read verses 59-
70. Then we're going to read 76 to 80.
Luke the first chapter,
we're going to read verses 59 to 70.
Then we going to skip to 76 down to
verse 80.
Luke 1
a few pages.
When you get it, my brother,
please read.
>> And it came to pass that on the eighth
day they came to circumcise the child,
and they called him Zachcharias after
the name of his father.
>> Come on. And his mother answered and
said, "Not so, but he shall be called
John."
>> Yes. Because the angel visited the
mother. And told the mother what? His
name is going to be called John. That
name came from heaven. Read.
>> And they said unto her, "There is none
of thy kindred that is called by his
name."
>> Yeah. Because that's what that's why you
see the names repeated a lot of times in
the Bible because they was recycling
those names. Go ahead. And they made
signs to his father how he would have
him called.
>> So if you didn't know, Zacharias was
made dumb where he couldn't speak.
>> So they were making signs to him trying
to say, "Hey man, he both be named after
you, Zacharias.
What happened?"
>> And he asked for a writing table and
wrote saying, "His name is John." And
they marveled all.
>> Whoa. Cuz he knew too where that name
came from. Go ahead.
>> And his mouth was opened immediately and
his tongue loosed and he spake and
praised God.
>> So look what the first thing came out of
his mouth was. Thank you, Lord. Praise
God.
>> Read.
>> And fear came on all that dwelt round
about them. And all these sayings were
noised abroad throughout all the hill
country of Judea.
And all they that heard them laid them
up in their hearts, saying, "What manner
of child shall this be?" And the hand of
the Lord was with him.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And his father Zachcharias was filled
with the Holy Ghost and prophesied,
saying,
>> "So look what happened to him. When he
was filled with the Holy Ghost, he
started talking.
>> He didn't run around and jump and dance
across the room and walk on the ceiling.
He started talking.
>> It said prophesying saying what?
>> Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for
he hath visited and redeemed his people
and hath raised up a horn of salvation
for us in the house of his servant
David.
>> Yes.
>> As he spake by the mouth of his holy
prophets which have been since the world
began.
>> Yes. So we see somebody talking about
them holy prophets again
>> in this New Testament.
Skip down to verse 76 and read.
>> And thou, child, shalt be called the
prophet of the highest. For thou shalt
go before the face of the Lord to
prepare his ways.
>> Yes.
>> To give knowledge of salvation unto his
people by the remission of their sins.
>> So that's what John, he was a
forerunner. Go ahead.
through the tender mercy of our God,
whereby the dayspring from on high hath
visited us, to give light to them that
sit in darkness and in the shadow of
death, to guide our feet into the way of
peace.
>> Yes.
>> And the child grew and waxed strong in
spirit, and was in the deserts till the
day of his shoeing onto Israel.
>> Yes. So now, let's move forward. That's
what John was. He was that forerunner.
Let's go to the book of John. John 5 and
we're going to read verses 30 to 36.
John 5
and we're going to read verses 30 to 36.
He was their forerunner. He came in to
let them know that he was coming.
He prepared to wait.
John 5,
the fifth chapter of John, and we're
going to read verses 30 to 36.
We're going to see something that Jesus
said.
We get it, my brother. John 5, give me
verse 30.
>> I can of mine own self do nothing. As I
hear, I judge. And my judgment is just
because. because I seek not mine own
will but the will of the father which
hath sent me.
>> Yes.
>> If I bear witness of myself, my witness
is not true.
>> That's right. Cuz he didn't come to bear
witness of himself. He came to to bear
witness of the father. He came to
introduce the father because the only
God that people that from the beginning
all the way up to now ever known was the
one named Jesus because he came in his
father's name. His name was Jehovah at
first.
But he told you, I come in my father's
name.
>> Read,
>> there is another that beareth witness of
me, and I know that the witness which he
witnessth of me is true.
>> Yes.
>> Ye sent unto John, and he bear witness
unto the truth.
>> Yes. Talking about John the Baptist, but
what?
>> But I received not testimony from man.
>> Yes.
>> But these things I say, that ye might be
saved.
>> Uh-huh. He was a burning and a shining
light. And he were willing for a season
to rejoice in his light.
>> Yes.
>> But I have greater witness than that of
John. For the works which the father
hath given me to finish, the same works
that I do bear witness of me that the
father hath sent me.
>> So look at that. He said, "The works
that I do bear WITNESS OF ME." WHY WILL
those works bear witness of him? Because
it's written IN THE LAW. WHAT HE WAS
going to do.
>> It's already written. That's why they
should have known who he was.
>> But it letting you know just like today,
just like back then, nobody was reading.
>> Let's go to Romans 13.
Romans the 13th chapter
and we're going to read verses 8 down to
verse 14.
Romans the 13th chapter.
I got five more after this one. Romans
and we're going to read verses 8 down to
14.
And you get it, my brother. Give me
Romans 13 verse 8.
>> Owe no man anything but to love one
another.
>> Yes.
>> For he that loveth another hath
fulfilled the law.
>> You fulfill the law. That's your words.
To love your brother. Love your neighbor
as thyself.
>> Read.
>> For this. Thou shalt not commit
adultery.
>> Yes.
>> Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false
witness. Thou shalt not covet. And if
there be any other commandment, it is
briefly comprehended in this saying,
namely, thou shalt love thy neighbor as
thyself.
>> Yes.
>> Love workketh no ill to his neighbor.
Therefore, love is the fulfilling of the
law.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And that knowing the time, that now it
is high time to awake out of sleep. For
now is is our salvation, nearer than
when we believed.
>> Uhhuh. The night is far spent. The day
is at hand. Let us therefore cast off
the works of darkness and let us put on
the armor of light.
>> So look, now it's telling us something
else. We need to put on the armor of
light.
>> That's the word again.
>> Read. Let us walk honestly as in the
day, not in rioting and drunkenness, not
in chambering and wanttonness, not in
strife and envying.
>> Yes.
>> But put ye on the Lord Jesus Christ, and
make not provision for the flesh to
fulfill the lust thereof.
>> Yes. So when you put on the Lord Jesus,
THAT'S YOUR ARMOR. THAT'S YOUR
PROTECTION.
Let's go to Ephesians 6. Let's look at
this arm.
Ephesians 6 and we're going to read
verses 10 to 18.
Ephesians
6 chapter.
We're going to read verses 10
down to verse
18.
We're going to look at this armor of
God.
Get it, my brother? Give me Ephesians 6
verse 10.
Finally, my brethren, be strong in the
Lord and in the power of his might.
>> Yes.
>> Put on the whole armor of God that ye
may be able to stand against the ws of
the devil.
>> Yes. So, we we everybody know this right
here, but a lot of times when you, like
I said, when we read to read another
law, a lot of times we hear it so much
we take it for granted. But we need to
make sure we hold these things true in
our mind.
cuz we going to get tested. You get
tested soon as you walk outside them
doors. You get tested inside these
doors.
>> But you got to have that armor on to
recognize. Go ahead, brother.
>> For we wrestle not against flesh and
blood, but against principalities,
against powers, against the rulers of
the darkness of this world, against
spiritual wickedness in high places.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Wherefore take unto you the whole armor
of God?
>> You got to have the whole armor. You
can't have not on just some of it. You
got to have all of it on. Go ahead.
>> That ye may be able to withstand in the
evil day and having done all to stand.
>> That's why sometime we wonder why we
going through things cuz we don't have
all the armor on.
>> How did that happen? HOW DID THAT GET
IN? I'M IN THE WORD. I GO TO SANTA
CLAIR. LORD, WHY?
Don't tell me you had to do a check. You
had to pick this mirror up.
I got a in my arm.
>> Read.
>> Stand therefore, having your loins girth
about with truth, and having on the
breastplate of righteousness.
>> Yes.
>> And your feet shaw with the preparation
of the gospel of peace.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Above all, taking the shield of faith.
>> So, look at that. Above all, take the
shield of faith. So you can have all
that other arm on, BUT IF YOU AIN'T GOT
NO FAITH,
YOU WASTING YOUR TIME. YOU MIGHT AS WELL
GO BACK HOME AND WASH YOUR car and go to
baby bae birthday party
>> cuz you wasting your time in here.
>> That's why I said read that verse again.
>> And your feet shine.
>> Uhuh. Verse 16.
>> Above all, taking the shield of faith.
>> Above all, taking the shield of faith,
what? wherewith ye shall be able to
quench all the fiery darts OF THE
WICKED.
>> ALL THE FIERY DOTS, not some of them.
>> SO IF YOU AIN'T GOT THAT FAITH AND YOUR
YOUR SHIELD AIN'T STRONG ENOUGH, THEM D
PENETRATED AND IT HIT you
>> cuz you're wavering in your faith.
Read
>> and take the helmet of salvation and the
sword of the spirit which is the word of
God. Yes, sir.
>> Praying always.
>> Or you giving me some tips.
>> Praying.
>> Praying always. What?
>> Praying always with all prayer and
supplication in the spirit and watching
there onto with all perseverance and
supplication for all saints.
>> So check this out. You can have that
full armor on and that shield of faith,
but if you ain't praying and you just
relying on that armor and you ain't
praying to the Lord and telling him what
you need and meaning what you say,
>> that don't do you no good either. It
said pray always,
>> not when some trouble come on, always
praying. Cuz guess what that prayer is
simply saying? Thank you, Jesus.
>> Thank you, Lord.
Let's go to Matthew 25.
We got three more after this. Matthew
25.
Matthew 25. We're going to read verses
1-13.
Matthew the 25th chapter.
We're going to read verses
one down to verse 13.
a few pages. Matthew 25, give me verse
one, my brother, when you get
>> then shall the kingdom of heaven be
likened unto 10 virgins, which took
their lamps, and went forth to meet the
bridegroom.
>> Yes, sir. So, y'all know we the bride,
>> right?
>> And Jesus is the groom.
Bread. And five of them were wise and
five were foolish.
>> That they that they that were foolish
took their lamps and took no oil with
them.
>> That's right. So why have a lamp and you
ain't got no oil?
>> Read.
>> But the wise took oil in their vessels
with their lamps.
>> So they took some oil. What? Wait, read
that again.
>> But the wise took oil in their vessels
with their lamps.
>> So they got oil in their lamps.
read.
>> While the bridegroom terried, they all
slumbered and slept.
>> So why the bridegroom tried? Because
what is what we just read? Say he coming
as a thief in the night.
>> So you going to have to be ready.
>> Read.
>> And at midnight there was a cry made,
behold the bridegroom cometh. Go ye out
to meet him.
>> Man, they done jumped up. But what
>> then all those virgins arose and trimmed
their lamps.
>> So they all arose and trimmed the lamp
and what?
>> And the foolish said unto the wise,
"Give us of your oil, for our lamps are
gone out."
>> So they didn't jumped up and trying to
trim their lamp. They got a flame that
didn't jumped up, but what didn't
happen? It went out cuz they ain't got
enough oil in there.
>> Go ahead. But the wise answered, saying,
"Not so, lest there be not enough for us
and you." But go ye rather to them that
sell, and buy for yourselves.
>> And while they went to buy, the
bridegroom came, and they that were
ready went in with him to the marriage,
and the door was shut.
Afterward came also the other virgins,
saying, Lord, Lord, open to us. But he
answered and said, "Verily, I say unto
you, I know you not."
>> Watch therefore, for ye know neither the
day nor the hour wherein the Son of Man
cometh.
>> Look at that. Better be ready.
>> We don't know when he coming.
>> We got things lined up. That's why we
keep the feast days. So, we have ideas
of this and ideas of that. But the
thing, man's time is always.
That's the problem right there. So, we
got an idea looking at the feast days,
how everything lined up, so on and so
forth. But if he take you right now and
your insurance policy ain't paid up,
>> YOU AIN'T READY.
>> YOU AIN'T HAVE NO OIL IN your lamp.
>> And now your resume already written out.
Some of us know we need some of that
stuff
erased off our resume.
2 Corinthians the 4th chapter. 2
Corinthians 4
and we're going to read verses 1
down to verse 10.
2 Corinthians the 4th chapter.
We going to read verse one. Y'all want
to start over?
2 Corinthians 4.
We going to read verses 1 down to verse
10. 2 Corinthians the 4th chapter. We're
going to read verses 1 down to verse 10.
And what y'all say? Brother Ch good, but
>> but but
2 Corinthians 4, give me verse one, my
brother, when you get it.
>> Therefore, seeing we have this ministry,
as we have received mercy, we faint not.
>> But have renounced the hidden things of
dishonesty, not walking in craftiness,
nor handling the word of God
deceitfully.
>> Man, that Go ahead and finish that up.
Go ahead. but by manifestation of the
truth, commending ourselves to every
man's conscience in the sight of God.
>> So that's what we got to watch out for.
Handling the word of God deceitfully
because trust you men.
There's a lot of brothers and a lot of
sisters out here that's handling this
word of God deceitfully.
That's why the book tell you a little
lev leavenvens the whole lump. talking
with some brothers in their
congregation. They had some people come
in and get that whispering and about all
them old false doctrines and end up
taking away from their congregation
because people sit there and listen to
it and buy into it and then believe it
or not it be some of the people that you
think is grounded in this word and it
took them right out of the door
cuz somebody handling the word of God
deceitfully.
So you have to be careful. That's why
when we we sniff it out in here, we
stomping it out.
>> Where we at?
>> We're at number three.
>> Go ahead.
>> But if our gospel be hid, it is hid to
them that are lost.
>> Yes.
>> In whom the God of this world hath
blinded the minds of them which believe
not, lest the light of the glorious
gospel of Christ, who is the image of
God, should shine onto them.
>> That's right. So if that light shining
on to you, you hey, you able to
recognize what's going on when they
bring that foolishness to you. Say, "Hey
man, get away from around me with that."
Say, "Hey, have you talked to Brother
Drake about that? Have you talked to
Brother Jeff, DeAndre, Josh, Alex?
>> Have you brought that to them brothers?"
Well, see, they all then you already
know they full of it.
>> Read.
>> For we pray. For we preach not
ourselves, but G Christ Jesus the Lord
and ourselves your servants for Jesus'
sake. For God who commanded the light to
shine out the dark, shine out of the
darkness has shined in our hearts to
give the light of the knowledge of the
glory of God in the face of Jesus
Christ.
>> Yes.
>> But we have this treasure in earthn
vessels that the excellency of the power
may be of God. earthly vessel. We got
this word in
>> this body.
>> This body read
>> and not of us. We are troubled on every
side.
>> Yes, we are.
>> Yet not distressed.
>> Come on.
>> We are perplexed but not in despair.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Persecuted but not forsaken. Cast down
but not destroyed.
>> Yes. always bearing about in the body
the dying of the Lord Jesus that the
life also of Jesus might be made
manifest in our body.
>> Yes sir.
>> So we go through it but guess what? We
always overcome.
>> Because we keeping God first.
>> Let's go to Isaiah 60. I got one more
after this one. Isaiah 60. We're going
to read verses 1-5. Then we're going to
skip down to verses 8 to 10.
Isaiah 60.
Why want to play with me now?
Isaiah 60. We're going to read verses
1-5. Then we going to skip down to
verses 8 to 10.
We got one more after this one, family.
When you get it, give me Isaiah 60 verse
one.
Arise, shine, for thy light is come and
the glory of the Lord is risen upon
thee.
>> Quick story real quick. Y'all see that?
Arise and shine. I know some of y'all
see it in the text that I send y'all.
Yes.
>> The reason I did it was because, you
know, you have so so many people kicking
against good morning,
>> which I have no earthly understanding
why they kick against good morning.
Because the way you spell m o r n and m
o r n, that's two different spellings,
two different means.
>> BUT ISRAEL WILL FALL FOR ANYTHING.
So I say, you know what? Arise and
shine, Israel.
>> Take it from the top.
>> Arise, shine, for thy light is come, and
the glory of the Lord is risen upon
thee.
>> Yes.
>> For behold, the darkness shall cover the
earth, and gross darkness the people,
but the Lord shall arise upon thee, and
his glory shall be seen upon thee.
>> Yes. And the Gentiles shall come to thy
light, and kings to the brightness of
thy rising.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Lift up thine eyes round about, and see.
All they gather themselves together.
They come to thee. Thy sons shall come
from afar, and thy daughters shall be
nursed at thy side.
>> Yes. Then thou shalt see and flow
together, and thine heart shall fear and
be enlarged, because the abundance of
the sea shall be converted unto thee.
The forces of the Gentiles shall come
unto thee.
>> So what we reading right here, this is
future. We reading the coming of the
Lord, and them Gentiles, what they going
to do? They going to bring you in. Same
way they brought you into the captivity,
they going to bring you into the Lord.
And we going to read some of that. Let's
go to verse eight. Skip down to eight
and read.
>> Who are these that fly as a cloud?
>> Yes.
>> And as the doves to their windows.
>> So we looking at he don't know what he
was looking at at that time, but we
looking at airplanes. So you wonder how
you going to get to that land and get to
that area. Airplane going to carry. We
know a dove ain't got no one.
If you see a dove flying, he got a oneo
on his side. Man, you might want to slap
yourself or stop taking that dope you
take
>> and I don't want none.
>> Keep reading.
>> Surely the isisle shall wait for me and
the ships of Tarsus.
>> The hole right there. And the ships of
Tarses. So those are the same ships that
the merchant men use. That's the same
way they're going to use to bring you
back to where you need to go.
>> Take that from the top. Surely the
isisles shall wait for me and the ships
of Tarsus first to bring thy sons from
afar, their silver and their gold with
them.
>> So look, THE SAME WAY WHEN YOU LEFT out
of Egypt, what the book said? YOU SPO
THE EGYPTIANS,
>> they gave you, huh? Take this with you.
HUH? TAKE THAT WITH YOU. THE SAME WAY
YOU GOING TO be coming with that. What?
What just say? You free them from the
top one more time. Surely the isisle
shall wait for me and the ships of
Tarses first to bring thy sons from
afar, their silver and their gold with
them onto the name of the Lord thy God,
and to the holy one of Israel, because
he hath glorified thee.
>> Yes.
>> And the sons of strangers shall build up
thy walls.
>> So look at the son of the stranger, that
gentile, he going to do what? He going
to rebuild the way he said it is. Amen.
>> So people always like to say he going to
be your slave. He's going to be a
servant. The same way you on the bottom
now, guess what? You going to be on top
and he's just going to work for you.
That's all it is. Cuz guess who got all
the possessions? Who got all the
equipment to build things?
>> They do.
>> Read. And their king shall minister unto
thee.
>> Yes.
>> For in my wrath I smoke thee, but in my
favor have I had mercy on thee.
Therefore, thy gates shall be open
continually, that they shall not be shut
day nor night, that men may bring unto
thee the forces of the Gentiles, and
that their kings may be brought.
>> All right, that's good.
>> That's good. But at the same time, I'm
just letting you know that, hey, all
knees going to bow down to the Lord.
>> Israel back on top again.
>> Let's go to our last place. Revelation
21.
Revelation 21. We're going to read
verses 1-5.
We're going to skip down to verses 9 to
12. And then we're going to skip to
verses 22 to 27.
Revelation the 21st chapter. We're going
to read verses 1-5. And then we're going
to do a little skip.
This our last place.
And let's we gonna see what kingdom we
dealing with right here. Because for
those that don't know, Jesus gonna have
his kingdom and he gonna reign a
thousand years in his kingdom.
>> And then after his kingdom, then we
going to see what's going to happen in
this Revelation 21. Give it to me, my
brother.
>> And I saw a new heaven and a new earth.
For the first heaven and the first earth
were passed away, and there was no more
sea.
>> Yes. And I, John, saw the holy city, New
Jerusalem, coming down from God out of
heaven, prepared as a bride adorned for
her husband.
>> Cuz that's what Jesus told you. I go and
prepare a place for you.
>> Not for you when you die, you going to
go there. But when this time come,
>> New Jerusalem coming down here on earth.
Read. And I heard a great voice out of
heaven, saying, "Behold, the tabernacle
of God is with men."
>> Is with men. And what?
>> And he will dwell with them, and they
shall be his people, and God himself
shall be with them.
>> Guess what? We talking about the Father.
>> Go ahead.
>> And be their God. And God shall wipe
away all tears from their eyes. And
there shall be no more death, neither
sorrow, nor crying, neither shall there
be any more pain, for the former things
are passed away.
>> Yes.
>> And he that sat upon the throne said,
"Behold, I make all things new." And he
said unto me, "Write, for these words
are true and faithful."
>> Yes, sir. Skip down to verse nine and
read.
And there came unto me one of the seven
angels, which had the seven vials full
of the seven last plagues, and talked
with me, saying, Come hither. I will
shoe thee the bride, the lamb's wife.
>> Yes.
>> And he carried me away in the spirit to
a great and high mountain, and shued me
that great city, the holy Jerusalem,
descending out of heaven from God.
>> Yes, sir. having the glory of God. And
her light was like unto a stone most
precious, even like a jasper stone,
clear as crystal.
>> Come on.
>> And had a wall great and high, and had
12 gates, and at the tw gates 12 angels,
and names written thereon, which are the
names of the 12 tribes of the children
of Israel.
>> Yeah. So going against what man tell you
one gate
>> and Peter sitting there with it quill
>> but it say got 12 gates and they going
to have the names of the 12 tribes of
Israel wrote on each gate.
>> Skip down. Was that verse 12?
>> Yes. Skip down to verse 22 and read.
>> And I saw no temple therein. For the
Lord God Almighty and the Lamb are the
temple of it.
>> Yes. Yes. And the city had no need of
the sun, neither of the moon to shine in
it. For the glory of God did lighten it,
and the Lamb is the light thereof.
>> Yes, it is.
>> And the na and the nations of them which
are saved shall walk in the light of it,
and the kings of the earth do bring
their glory and honor into it.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And the gates of it shall not be shut at
all by day, for there shall be no night
there. and they shall bring the glory
and honor of the nations into it. And
there shall in no wise enter into it
anything that defileth, neither
whatsoever workketh abomination or
maketh a lie, but they which are written
in the Lamb's book of life.
>> Yes. So that's your goal today is make
sure you are written in the Lamb's book
of life. Amen.
>> So, with that said, that concludes this
lesson. This light of mine, I'm going to
let it shine. I hope somebody got
something out of it. Thank you for your
time.
Heat. Heat.